<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog on Astro-statistics</title>
    <link>https://bioscience.netlify.app/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog on Astro-statistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bioscience.netlify.app/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to find your Genes</title>
      <link>https://bioscience.netlify.app/2020/09/14/where-to-find-your-genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bioscience.netlify.app/2020/09/14/where-to-find-your-genes/</guid>
      <description>We’ve been working with the genetics of schizophrenia, looking at how the expression of genes that play a role in the condition vary across brain regions and neurodevelopment stages. Now, call me old-fashioned, but I like to know how things are laid out, so in this case where these genes are situated. Time for a plot.
The genes in question come from a GWAS study of the PGC. The images are build based on the ggbio and karyoploteR packages from bioconductor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Data Visualisation Introduction Lecture</title>
      <link>https://bioscience.netlify.app/2020/09/12/01-data-visualisation-introduction-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bioscience.netlify.app/2020/09/12/01-data-visualisation-introduction-lecture/</guid>
      <description>class: center, inverse
Course Contents System Configuration - installing software Using RStudio Introduction to R Getting and Cleaning Data Exploratory Analysis - making rough plots Different Types of Plots Playing with Aesthetics Using Plotting Themes Advanced Topics - Maps, Networks  Why We’re Here  Alternative to Excel Enables Reproducible Research Can Make Lots of Plots Quickly  Good for Exploratory Analysis  Publication Ready Figures   And….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteorites, and Where to Find Them</title>
      <link>https://bioscience.netlify.app/2020/09/12/meteorites-and-where-to-find-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bioscience.netlify.app/2020/09/12/meteorites-and-where-to-find-them/</guid>
      <description>body, h1, h2, h3, h4 { font-family: &#34;California FB&#34;, serif; } body { color: #00004b; } a, a:hover { color: #8b1a1a; } p, pre { font-size: 16px; }  This analysis was inspired by a set of talks by Mike Brown of Caltech on small bodies in the Solar System (these are available as part of his course on The Science of the Solar System on Coursera).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>