<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog on Astro-statistics</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog on Astro-statistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tennis Sets - Jimmy&#39;s Theorem</title>
      <link>/2020/09/14/tennis-sets-jimmy-s-theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/14/tennis-sets-jimmy-s-theorem/</guid>
      <description>The Concept Our tennis coach has a theory. As well as being a teacher and player he’s also an avid follower of the game. And he reckons that an inordinate amount of competitive, two-set tennis matches finish with a closely matched first set followed by a relative blow out in the second. 7-5, 6-2 just about covers it.
Jimmy’s thinking is that a player who loses the first set, however close it was, will try to change things up to rescue the match.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to find your Genes</title>
      <link>/2020/09/14/where-to-find-your-genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/14/where-to-find-your-genes/</guid>
      <description>We’ve been working with the genetics of schizophrenia, looking at how the expression of genes that play a role in the condition vary across brain regions and neurodevelopment stages. Now, call me old-fashioned, but I like to know how things are laid out, so in this case where these genes are situated. Time for a plot.
The genes in question come from a GWAS study of the PGC. The images are build based on the ggbio and karyoploteR packages from bioconductor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Data Visualisation Introduction Lecture</title>
      <link>/2020/09/12/01-data-visualisation-introduction-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/12/01-data-visualisation-introduction-lecture/</guid>
      <description>class: center, inverse
Course Contents System Configuration - installing software Using RStudio Introduction to R Getting and Cleaning Data Exploratory Analysis - making rough plots Different Types of Plots Playing with Aesthetics Using Plotting Themes Advanced Topics - Maps, Networks  Why We’re Here  Alternative to Excel Enables Reproducible Research Can Make Lots of Plots Quickly  Good for Exploratory Analysis  Publication Ready Figures   And…. a gateway to so much more  data capture statistical analysis machine learning artificial intelligence writing your thesis writing a blog   Not Why We’re Here  Won’t discuss choices for data presentation Nor good practices in visualisations  but these are sort of in the background  This isn’t a machine learning course  but lots of the techniques we’ll use are relevant  So, this course it about skills development, how you use these is up to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteorites, and Where to Find Them</title>
      <link>/2020/09/12/meteorites-and-where-to-find-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/12/meteorites-and-where-to-find-them/</guid>
      <description>body, h1, h2, h3, h4 { font-family: &#34;California FB&#34;, serif; } body { color: #00004b; } a, a:hover { color: #8b1a1a; } p, pre { font-size: 16px; }  This analysis was inspired by a set of talks by Mike Brown of Caltech on small bodies in the Solar System (these are available as part of his course on The Science of the Solar System on Coursera).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>